Rockbridge Historical Society files on genealogy RHS.Coll.0058
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
Rockbridge Historical Society files on genealogy
1700-1960
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
RHS.Coll.0058
9 Box
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research use.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains biographical and genealogical information on various people, primarily from in and around Rockbridge County.
Genealogy; Photography
- A-B (Box 1, Folder 1-17)
  Scope and Contents
  This box includes folders on Lucy P. Ackerly, the Alexander family, the Anderson family, the Baker family, the Beard family, James Beatty, the Bell family, the Bogan family, the Borden family, the Bowyer family, the Brooke family, and the Brown family.
  - Ackerly, Lucy Pauline (Box 1, Folder 1)
    This folder contains applications to the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution and related documents.
    Daughters of the American Revolution
  - Alexander, Archibald (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Alexander, Archibald
  - Alexander, Robert (Box 1, Folder 3)
    This folder contains information about the family of Robert Alexander (brother of Archibald Alexander).
    Alexander, Robert, Sr.; Alexander, Archibald
  - Alexander, William (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alexander Family (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Alexander family; Alexander, Robert, Sr.; Alexander, Archibald; Alexander, John, Major; Alexander, Andrew; Alexander, James
  - Alexander Family (McCulloch notes) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Alexander family
  - Anderson Family (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Anderson family; Anderson, Francis Thomas; Anderson, John Thomas; Anderson, William Alexander
  - Baker Family (Box 1, Folder 8)
    This folder contains photocopied indentures involving the Baker family.
  - Beard, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 9)
    This folder contains the last will and testament of Thomas Beard.
    Alexander, Robert, Sr.
  - Beatty, James (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bell Family (Box 1, Folder 11)
    This folder contains a letter inquiring about details concerning the murder of Joseph Bell and his wife.
  - Bogan Family (Box 1, Folder 12)
    This folder contains a book about the history of the Bogan family, including the etymology of their name, burial locations, marriage information, and a list of births.
  - Borden Family (Box 1, Folder 13)
    This folder contains information about the Borden family and an inquiry about their possible relation to Lizzie Borden, famed murder suspect.
    Borden family; Borden, Benjamin, Sr.
  - Bowyer Family (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Bowyer, John, General; Bowyer, Otis
  - Bowyer Family (Box 1, Folder 15)
    This folder contains information on the Bowyers living in "Thorn Hill," a house outside of Lexington.
    Bowyer, Otis; Bowyer, John, General
  - Brooke Family (Box 1, Folder 16)
    This folder contains information on the Brooke family, including a family crest and newspaper articles.
  - Brown Family, Turner, Charles W. (Charles Wilson) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    This folder contains information about the Brown family plot and vault in Woodland Cemetery, including photocopied photographs. Also enclosed is correspondence between George T. Brown, Jr. and the Rockbridge Historical Society concerning data on the Brown and Kirkham families.
    Brown Family
- Campbell Family, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  Campbell family
  - Clan Campbell Society Newsletter, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Journal of Clan Campbell Society, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- C (Box 3, Folder 1-9)
  This box includes folders on the Cahoon family, the Campbell family, the Carr family, the Caruthers family, the Clyce family, the Coffey family, and the Crawford family.
  - Cahoon Family (Box 3, Folder 1)
    This folder contains census records and ancestor charts concerning the Cahoon family.
  - Campbell Family (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Campbell Family (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, David (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Carr Family (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Caruthers Family (Box 3, Folder 6)
    This folder contains the history of the Caruthers family, including the granting of a slave to Rebecca Caruthers, the wife of Samuel Caruthers, and the granting of slaves to the daughters and granddaughters of Captain John Caruthers.
    Caruthers family; Caruthers, William Alexander; Caruthers, John
  - Clyce Family (Box 3, Folder 6A)
    This folder contains pamphlets about a lodge run by the Clyce family as well as correspondence between Charles McCulloch and Harold F. Clyce.
    Clyce Family
  - Coffey Family (Box 3, Folder 7)
    This folder contains a photocopy of a page from the Coffey family Bible.
    Coffey Family
  - Crawford Family (Box 3, Folder 8)
    This folder contains the history of the Crawford family, inlcuding a land grant (issued by then governor of Virginia, James Monroe) concerning their estate.
    Crawford Family
  - Crawford Family (Box 3, Folder 9)
- D-G (Box 4, Folder 1-27)
  This box includes folders on the Davidson family, the Deacon family, the Dickerson family, Daniel Dod, the Dorman family, the Downing family, the Estill family, the Ewing family, the Firestone family, the Gibbs family, the Gillispie family, the Glasgow family, the Goodson family, the Gordon family, the Graham family, the Grant family, the Graybill family, the Greenlee family, and the Grigsby family.
  - Davidson, Greenlee (Box 4, Folder 1)
    This folder contains the history of Greenlee Davidson's extended family, including their involvement the Siege of Derry and the Civil War.
    Davidson, Greenlee; Davidson family
  - Davidson Family (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Davidson family
  - Deacon Family (Box 4, Folder 3)
    This folder contains a history of the Deacon family and a check received by William D. Deacon for Buffalo County Schools.
  - Dickerson Family (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Dickerson family
  - Dod, Daniel (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dorman Family, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    This folder contains two letters between a "Dr. Turner" and Jane B. Lacey concerning the Dorman family.
  - Downing Family (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Estill Family (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ewing Family (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Firestone Family (Box 4, Folder 10)
    This folder contains family group records and an application to the Daughters of the American Revolution.
  - Gay Family (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gibbs Family (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gillispie Family (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Glasgow Family (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Glasgow family
  - Goodson Family (Box 4, Folder 15)
    This folder contains a photocopied page from the Goodson family Bible.
  - Gordon Family (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Gordon Family
  - Graham Family (Box 4, Folder 17)
    This folder contains various newspaper articles concerning the Graham family.
    Graham family
  - Grant Family (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Graybill Family (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Greenlee Family (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Greenlee family
  - Greenlee Family (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Grigsby Family (Box 4, Folder 22)
    This folder contains newsletters and a roster of members from the National Grigsby Family Society.
    Grigsby family
  - Grigsby Family (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Grigsby Family (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Grigsby family; Grigsby, Reuben
  - Grigsby Family (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Grigsby Family (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Grigsby Family (including Paxton family) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Grigsby family; Paxton family
- H-K (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
  This box contains folders on the Hickman family, the Hileman family, the Houston family, the Hunter family, the Jackson family, the Jordan family, the Keffer family, the Kerr family, the Kessler family, the Kinnear family, the Kirkham family, the Kirkpatrick family, and the Krebs family.
  - Hickman Family (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hickman Family (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hileman Family (Box 5, Folder 3)
    This folder contains pedigree charts and family group records concerning the Hileman family.
  - Houston Family, Plecker, Adam (Box 5, Folder 4)
    This folder contains a student notebook containing the history of the Houston family written by H.I. Houston as well as a carte de visite photograph of the Houston family coat of arms taken by Adam Plecker, a regional traveling photographer.
    Photography -- Printing processes -- Albumen; Carte de visite photographs; Photography; Houston family
  - Hunter Family (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Hunter, Samuel
  - Jackson Family (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Jackson family
  - Jordan Family (Box 5, Folder 7)
    This folder contains photographs of Jordan family tombstones located in the Stonewall Jackson Cemetery.
    Photography; Jordan Family; Stonewall Jackson Cemetery (Lexington, Va.)
  - Keffer Family (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Kerr (Carr) Family (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kerr (Carr), Richard (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kessler Family (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Kinnear Family (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Kirkham Family (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kirkpatrick Family (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Kirkpatrick family
  - Krebs Family (Box 5, Folder 15)
- L-M (Box 6, Folder 1-32)
  This box contains documents on James Lackey, the Lacy family, the Laird family, the Lee family, the Leech family, the Little family, the Lyle family, the Lynn family, the McClung family, the McClure family, the McCorkle family, the McCormick family, Thomas McCoy, Ephraim McDowell, the McFadden family, the McKee family, the McNutt family, the Mackey family, John Marshall, the Miller family, the Mills family, the Moffett family, and the Moore family.
  - Lackey, James, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lacy Family (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Laird Family (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Laird, Thomas Harvey, 1812-1859; Laird, Alexander Thompson, 1819-1861; Laird, Edward Chambers, 1854-1938
  - Lee Family (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Lee family
  - Leech Family (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Little Family (Box 6, Folder 6)
    This folder contains a history of the Little family, including their ties with the Lee family.
    Lee family; Lee, William; Little, Martha
  - Lyle Family (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lyle Family (Box 6, Folder 8)
    This folder contains a bound book of some Lyle family records and a photograph (c. 1968) of four Lyle family portraits (c. 1925).
    Photography
  - Lynn (Linn) Family (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - McClung Family (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - McClung Family (Box 6, Folder 12)
    This folder contains handwritten notes on the family of Julian and Nora McClung, family photos, a notice of military selection, enlistment record, and discharge papers for Julian McClung in World War I.
    Photography; World War (1914-1918); McClung, Clyde Julian, 1892-1976
  - McClure Family (Box 6, Folder 13)
    This folder contains an account of a 1785 Native American attack and the scalping of McClure children in Lincoln County, Kentucky. There is also the last will and testament of John McClure which includes the sale of a slave named Anthony conditional upon the remarriage of McClure's wife or the coming of age of his youngest child.
    Kentucky; McClure Family
  - McCormick Family (Box 6, Folder 14)
    McClure Family
  - McCorkle Family (Box 6, Folder 15)
    This folder contains newspaper clippings concerning members of the McCorkle family including Lt. Baxter McCorkle, as well as an address delivered at Louisville before the Virginia Society in Kentucky on Washington's birthday.
  - McCorkle, Henry H. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - McCoy, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - McCoy, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - McCoy, Thomas (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - McDowell, Ephraim (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - McFadden Family (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - McKee Family (Box 6, Folder 22)
    This folder contains information on the McKee family, including a map of Galloway (Southwestern Scotland).
  - McNutt Family (Box 6, Folder 23)
    This folder contains a collection of photographs of property owned by the McNutt family.
    Photography; McNutt family
  - McNutt Family (Box 6, Folder 24)
    McNutt family
  - Mackey Family (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Marshall, John (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Miller, Henry
  - Miller Family (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Miller family
  - Mills Family (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Moffett Family (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Moore Family (Box 6, Folder 31)
    Moore Family
  - Moore Family (Box 6, Folder 32)
- N-S (Box 7, Folder 1-26)
  This box contains information about the Newcomb family, the Patton family, the Paxton family, the Pendleton family, the Poage family, the Quaintance family, the Randolph family, Andrew Reid, the Reblogel family, the Reynolds and McGuire families, the Roach family, the Salling family, John Saville, the Shafer family, the Shanks family, the Sheltman family, the Smith family, the Sterrett family, the Stuart family, and the Swope family.
  - Newcomb Family (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Newcomb Family
  - Patton Family (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Paxton Family (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Paxton family
  - Paxton Family (Box 7, Folder 4)
    This folder contains information on John and Phebe Paxton, and discusses their ownership of slaves. It also contains inscriptions on various Paxton tombstones.
    Paxton family; Paxton, Alexander Sterrett; Paxton, John; Paxton, Samuel A.; Paxton, Phebe Alexander; Paxton, William; Paxton, Thomas, 1722-1788; Alexander, Archibald
  - Paxton Family (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Paxton family; Paxton, Thomas, 1722-1788; Paxton, Samuel A.; Paxton, John
  - Paxton, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Paxton, Thomas, 1722-1788
  - Pendleton Family (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Pendleton, James Dudley; Pendleton family
  - Pendleton Family (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Pendleton family
  - Pendleton Family (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pendleton Family (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Poage Family (Box 7, Folder 11)
    This folder contains a cardboard memorial placard for Nancy Poague.
  - Quaintance Family (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Randolph Family (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Randolph, John; Randolph, Edmund
  - Reid, Andrew (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Reid family; Reid, Andrew, Jr.; Reid, Andrew
  - Reblogel Family (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Reynolds and McGuire Family (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Roach Family (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Salling Family (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Salling Family
  - Saville, John and Sarah (Shaffer) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Shafer Family (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Shanks Family (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Sheltman Family (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Smith Family (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Sterrett Family (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Stuart Family (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Stuart family
  - Swope Family (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Templeton Family (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Album of Mary Lou McCampbell, 1859 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    This folder contains an album that was a Christmas present to Mary Lou McCampbell containing handwritten poetry.
  - Templeton Photographs (Box 8, Folder 2)
    This folder contains loose photographs and a carte de visite album of various members of the Templeton, Gibbs, and Lilley families. Included in the album are carte de visite photographs of Confederate General Robert Doak Lilley.
    Photography; McCampbell family; Templeton, James; Lilley, Robert Doak, 1836 - 1886
  - Templeton Family Documents (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Ter-Z (Box 9, Folder 1-23)
  This box contains information on the Terry family, the Todd family, the Tolley family, the Waddell family, the Walker family, the Walkup family, the Wallace family, the Wardlaw family, the Waskey family, the Weaver family, the Weir family, the Welch family, Ki Williams, the Willson/Wilson family, the Woods family, the Youel family, and Brian Young.
  - Terry Family (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Todd Family (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tolley (Gillispie) Family (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Tolley Family
  - Tolley (Tolly) Family (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Waddell Family (Box 9, Folder 5)
    This folder contains letters between members of the Waddell family as well as a photograph of Benjamin Harrison Waddell.
    Photography; Waddell family; Waddell, Benjamin Harrison; Waddell, Maude; Waddell, Harrington
  - Waddell Family (Box 9, Folder 6)
    This folder contains some family records of the Houston, Waddell, and Estill families, addressed to the Rockbridge Historical Society.
    Waddell family; Houston family
  - Walker Family, 1804-02-20 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    This folder contains a section of the will of John Walker.
    Walker family
  - Walkup Family (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Houston family
  - Wallace Family (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Wallace family
  - Wallace Family (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Wardlaw Family (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Waskey Family (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Weaver Family (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Weaver family
  - Weaver, William (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Weir Family (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Weir family
  - Welch Family (Box 9, Folder 16)
    This folder contains a photograph of the Welch house and affidavits involving H. Jackson Darst and H. Middleton Raynal.
    Photography; Welch family; Welsh family
  - Williams, Ki (Box 9, Folder 17)
    This folder contains an application for the Delaware chapter of the National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution and related documents regarding Ki Williams and his ancestor, John Grier.
    Williams, Ki
  - Willson Family (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Willson Family
  - Wilson Family (Box 9, Folder 19)
    This folder contains negatives of Wilson family genealogies.
    Photography -- Negatives; Wilson family
  - Woods Family (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Wallace family; Walker family
  - Youel Family (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Youel family
  - Youel Family (Box 9, Folder 22)
    This folder contains issues of The Youel Log, imprints published by Youel Care, Inc. concerning the Youel family.